[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOTS]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
[METAL RODS CLANGING]
- [ENGINE REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
I don't think we'll get
anything out of this.
We need to think of other ways
to help Gabo.
I know a place! We'll surely
make a lot of money there.
What are we going
to be doing there?
Male strippers.
All the rich gays go here.
The long-haired one
is my type!
This is Mama Franny.
She's a big-time customer.
Why are you working
in a place like this?
My father needs
to undergo surgery.
How much, Gabo?
I'm not that type of person.
[BONES CRUNCHING]
[SCREAMING] Ahh!
What happened, Gabo?!
I'm being groped by gay men!
And they still want
to get what they want!
It's so hard to help you, Gabo.
Did I ask for your help?
I can take care of myself!
We've been keeping an eye
on you for a long time now.
What do you need from me?
[GROANS]
- [GUNSHOTS]
- Stay down!
Wait, no!
- What do you need from me?
- Gabo, wait!
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Gabo!
Tatang?
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Let me explain everything.
Omeng?
Tomas?
How did you
get out of jail?
That's Uwak.
And that's Lawin.
They are my messengers.
They monitored your every move.
What does this mean?
Are they with you?
Gabo.
Out here
we don't call him Tatang.
We call him Papang.
Just call him Pops.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
But how did you
get out of jail?
He's free to leave prison
any time he wants.
To find new members
of our group.
The Anino.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
What does this mean?
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
[THUDS]
- [THUDS]
- Why won't it work?
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
[DRAWER THUDS]
[SIGHS]
Sam.
What's going on?
Are you okay?
What's the problem?
- Nothing. Karen?
- Yes?
Is everything set
for the presentation later?
Yes, ma'am, almost complete.
Almost complete?
What does that mean?
Is it complete?
Is something missing?
Our report is later!
We are waiting
for Borromeo's reports
when they went to Chinatown.
Well, where are they?
- They're here!
- Oh great, they're here!
Guys, update?
We went to
the jewelry stores in Chinatown.
And?
There are shops there
that sell jewelry at low prices.
They also sell them
to online sellers.
All of the stores there
are owned by a
man named Mr. Chan.
We also did a background
check on him.
He has been
charged with tax evasion
But he gets away with it.
He seems to have a strong
connections in the government.
Alright, this is what we'll do.
I want a printed report.
We need to learn about that.
Where's Rallos?
- Rallos? Come here.
- Yes, ma'am!
I need some information
about Mr. Chan.
All of his connections
and his public records.
That needs to be included
in the report later.
- Yes, ma'am, on it.
- Okay.
- [BULLET] Why are you so tense?
Yeah, why are you panicking?
We shouldn't make a mistake
in our report later.
Someone will be sitting in
on our briefing.
- Who?
[UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Hi, guys!
[PIA] Well?
It's like you've seen a ghost.
I'm right here.
No one even greeted me.
Um...
Good evening, Ma'am Pia.
[UNEASY MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CLEARS THROAT]
The briefing is in 10 minutes.
Are you ready?
Yes.
I really hope you are.
Tick.
Tock.
[UNEASY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Oh no.
She became a clock.
- [CLAPS]
- Hurry up!
- Yes, Ma'am.
- Let's go.
We can do it,
Tick tock.
- [CLAPS]
- Let's go. [CHUCKLES]
[UNEASY MUSIC CONTINUES]
[PIA] Sir!
Oh, Pia.
What's up?
Are you ready for...
the briefing of...
your favorite agent?
I just hope she doesn't
embarrass you.
She knows that you'll
be there for the briefing.
Sam is detail-oriented.
She'll never embarrass me
with how she handles the case.
Well, I do hope... [SCOFFS]
that you made the right choice
to trust her.
[BREATHES SHARPLY]
Sebastian's there anyway.
In my eyes, he's miles better
compared to Sam.
There's no need to compare.
All of my agents are excellent.
We'll see about that.
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CREAKING CLOSE]
The demolition they did
at Ginintuang Lupa earlier
was horrible.
They treated those people
as if they're animals.
Just to get them to leave.
My friend, take it easy!
You're way too affected by it.
We went there to cover
all the events that happened.
Wait, do you live there?
Do you have relatives
who live there?
[THUDS, SIGHS]
I don't, Oli.
But of course, I can sympathize
with them.
They don't have much
on them to begin with.
- [THUDS]
- Well, Salvador,
it's all part of the job.
Keep your feelings separated
from the issue!
You shouldn't be too invested
with everything!
Especially with your job.
[EXHALES DEEPLY] I don't know...
Salvador.
Sir Arnel is calling for you.
Oh? See?
Our executive producer
is calling for us.
Why? For what?
I'm sure that it's because
of those feelings you have.
Feelings!
- [THUDS]
- [SALVADOR] Let's go.
- You yap way too much.
- [OLI SIGHS]
- [SALVADOR, INAUDIBLE]
- Oh, man.
- [OLI] Boss?
- [SALVADOR] Boss!
[OLI] Uh, they said you
wanted to talk to us?
Take a seat.
Oh, thank you, boss.
Oh, man. [CLEARS THROAT, CLAPS]
How was the coverage
of the Ginintuang Lupa
demolition for you two?
It was awful, boss, truly.
Everyone was fighting.
You'd think there's a war.
We even got caught in the middle
with the police.
[OLI] Boss! [LAUGHS]
Salvador and I did our big one
on this coverage!
- The best! [LAUGHING]
- [CLAPS]
[CLATTERS]
That's it?!
No executive producer
would be happy hearing that!
There are a lot of reporters
who cover
the eruption of a volcano!
Some of them even almost get
washed away by a tsunami!
And this is your report?
Are you proud of it?
Boss, listen.
We covered everything.
What happened was very real.
You covered it indeed
but did anyone bother watching
your lousy report?
You've been in the industry
for years, Salvador!
I've been watching you
ever since I was in college!
You know what kind of product
you should be creating!
What we need
is controversial news!
Sensational!
Something that feels as if
you're watching a melodrama!
Wh-- what do you want, boss?
For me to distort the facts?
I'm not that kind
of person, boss.
You're an employee
of the company!
Your responsibility is not
to the truth
but to the ratings and income
of the company
that's paying you.
Make a follow-up report on this!
A story that's worthwhile!
Roger, boss.
Thank you. Let's go, Oli.
You're worthwhile, Oli.
[SALVADOR] Telebalita viewers,
we're currently here
at Ginintuang Lupa
where the police has begun
their demolition operation.
The supposed peaceful
and orderly demolition
turned into a massive chaos
due to someone firing a gun.
Sir.
[SMACKS]
We're the bad guys again.
They should be thankful
we didn't fire back
at those bastards.
You should get used
to them always antagonizing us.
What's important...
is that the demolition
didn't push through.
Sir.
We will lose a lot
if we lose Ginintuang Lupa.
Why do you have to listen
to General Jacinto anyway?
I'm just trying to give back
to him
because if it weren't for him,
I wouldn't be
in this position now.
[SIGHS]
Sir, if you were to choose...
General Jacinto's words
or Ginintuang Lupa?
Which will you choose?
[MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Next time, I will choose myself.
And I am catering to everyone
who needs me, am I not?
But if those two
were to collide...
and I had to let go
of the other...
I'll choose the one...
that'll be beneficial to me
in the long run.
[DJANGO] Pa.
That Umali...
he didn't stick to our deal.
He even supports the demolition
of Ginintuang Lupa!
As if they don't benefit
from using us.
You know how those cops are.
If the won't gain anything
from it, they don't care.
Why?
We have something
to throw at them anyway!
Money!
If you think about it, they're
benefiting off of us a lot.
[PAQUITO] You know,
our deal with the police
is crystal clear.
They will protect us
and we'll pay them.
To what extent will they
protect us?
With mere words?
You know what? I think,
once they see an opening,
they'll betray us for sure.
[PAQUITO] I'd like
to see them try!
Don't they know that...
people in Ginintuang Lupa
are ruthless?
Try me.
They don't know what's coming.
Pa...
I know we have an arrangement
with the police,
but I hope they don't fool us.
Because no one is more clever
than us criminals!
Even if they're the police,
[GUN COCKS]
I won't let them get away.
[LAUGHS MANIACALLY]
[THUDS]
He's your son, no doubt.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING, FADES]
[PAPANG] Our country
is too chaotic, son.
The chaos around is rampant.
Even our government...
can't contain the surge
of criminals anymore.
And sometimes,
the criminals
are already working
with those in power.
Even the police.
They can't do anything about it.
That's why Anino is here.
To help clean our country.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
We need someone
who is wholehearted.
A good fighter, fearless,
and someone integrity.
We need you, Gabo.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
We've been watching you
for a long time, Gabo.
[OMENG] And Macaraig?
He's one of us.
He's in charge of screening
potential members.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Pops, how long are you
planning to stay inside?
It depends.
Until I find someone who has
potential to be part of Anino.
Once you do, tell us right away,
so we can help seize him up.
Pops.
[STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ECHOING THWACK, BLOWS LAND]
[PAPANG] I recruited
the wrong guy for Anino.
Now, I'm looking
for his replacement.
There are many thugs here
who are willing to kill
and can take on your orders.
Yes, there are a lot
of brave souls here,
but only a few of them have
the heart of a true warrior.
[THWACKS]
[THUDS]
[STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[THWACKS]
[BLOWS THWACKING]
[WHOOSHING]
- [METAL GRILLS CLANG]
- [BLOWS LAND]
- Tatang, Pedro's here.
- Hey.
[PAPANG] Come in.
[PEDRO] Tatang, good evening.
Have a seat.
Tomorrow, I want you to stab me
at the basketball court.
What are you planning, Tatang?
I just want to test someone.
Gabo.
- [STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [OVERLAPPING SHOUTING]
[PAPANG] Wait for my signal.
[INMATES SHOUTING]
[MUSIC BUILDS]
[PUNCHES LANDING]
[INMATE] Hey!
- [INMATES SHOUTING]
- [BLOWS, KICKS LANDING]
[FLESH RIPS]
[KICKS, BLOWS LANDING]
[OMENG] Gabo!
Tatang got stabbed!
Get him out of here!
- Hurry!
- [PAPANG GRUNTS]
- [INMATES CONTINUE SHOUTING]
- [TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[ECHOING BLOW]
[PAPANG] We put you
through many tests, Gabo.
[GABO] What's this?!
What are you doing to me?
[WARDEN] I heard you're tough.
- Let's see about that!
- [GABO GRUNTS]
[PAPANG] To make sure you're
the perfect person for the job.
[WARDEN] Dunk him!
- [GRUNTS]
- [LOUD SPLASH]
- [ELECTRICITY CRACKING]
- [LAWIN] You sure are tough.
You went through
so many challenges,
- but you survived it all.
- [GABO SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[UWAK]
We thought you wouldn't last.
[PAPANG]
But we saw your skill.
[GABO SCREAMING]
[PAPANG] Strength, grit...
[MEN SHOUTING]
[PAPANG]
You aren't just tough, Gabo.
You also have the conviction
to stand by your principles.
Gabo, tonight's your chance
to escape.
Gabo, here's the key.
Once everyone's asleep,
crawl your way out.
You have to escape now.
Otherwise, you won't make it
till sunrise in here.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
[GABO] I won't escape.
I'll stay and stand by...
...the truth.
[THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[GABO] Do you mean to say...
...you were behind all of that?
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
You ****** with me!
You should've just been upfront!
You could've faced me
man to man!
Gabo, don't forget that Anino
gave you your freedom back.
[PAPANG] I've tested Gabo.
No one else is more suited
to join Anino.
Copy, Pops.
I hope you're betting
on the right person now.
I can already see it.
He won't let me down.
[PAPANG] You think it's easy
to get paroled?
Your case was hopeless, boy.
You were up against
a politician.
And if they wanted you
to rot in jail,
they could've made it happen.
But Anino made the arrangements
for your release.
Gabo, I'm aware of your case.
You're also a victim
of the system.
And I believe that will push you
to work with us.
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[OMENG]
Gabo, Anino needs you
to act as their hands
in taking down criminals.
Gabo, Anino pays well
for every mission you complete.
Nothing stays hidden from us,
Gabo.
We know exactly what
you've been going through
ever since you got out
of prison.
You tried to turn your life
around, didn't you?
But you couldn't land
any decent job at all.
And now your father's in
the hospital, isn't that right?
And you need money
for his treatment, don't you?
Macaraig almost beat me to
death back inside that prison.
Turns out he was
just playing me.
Set me up good.
Yeah, I need cash.
I need work.
But not like this.
Hold on.
Leave us alone for a moment.
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm sorry, Gabo,
we didn't mean to keep
the truth from you at first.
But it's all part of screening
new members into Anino.
Tatang...
I want to change.
This work
will change everything,
for you, and it'll lift up
your whole family too.
[THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING]
One hundred thousand
per mission, Gabo.
to join Anino fully.
[THRILLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Let me think about it.
[MUSIC BECOMES DRAMATIC]
Gabo, how's your father doing?
He's not doing well at all.
Everything's gone wrong for
him, lost his mother already,
and now his father
gets shot like this.
That was pure police brutality
what you did there!
There was no police brutality
happening here!
- [OVERLAPPING SHOUTS]
- What?!
He needs surgery right away.
But we have no money.
I won't survive it if Rudy dies.
I thought for sure
I was finally free...
But turns out my freedom...
...came with a heavy price tag.
By opening this file,
you confirm you accept
and take on this mission.
Our intel confirms we can
take down the syndicate
involved in
the gold smuggling case.
The man shown
in this photo is Victor Zafra.
He goes by the alias "Tiger."
- Whoo!
- Go on, finish him off!
He's the alleged leader
of the illegal gold mining.
That's enough!
Tiger is huge game,
we absolutely cannot fail.
Your mission, Gabo,
it to bring Victor Zafra to us,
dead or alive.
This is our mission.
Failure is not an option.